Mary Metlay Kaufman Papers, 1917-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS AND CONFERENCES, (1946-88); 5 linear feet
  Other organizations represented include the International Association of Democratic Lawyers; the Lawyers' Committee on Nuclear Policy; the Lawyers' Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam; and the National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression. Kaufman was invited to take part in several international tribunals investigating U.S. war crimes. In 1967, she represented the National Lawyers' Guild at the International War Crimes Tribunal on American Involvement in Vietnam in Paris, sponsored by the Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation. She was a member of an international team of experts invited to Japan to investigate "the full implications of the use of the atom bomb over Hiroshima and Nagasaki," in 1977. And in 1984, Kaufman served on the International Tribunal on the Reagan Administration's Foreign Policy, sponsored by the International Progress Organization, in Brussels.
- SERIES VI. WRITINGS, (1966-83); .5 linear ft.
  This series contains published articles, unpublished drafts, notes, and research materials arranged alphabetically by title or topic. A recurring topic of Kaufman's writings is Nuremberg and the war crimes principles as they relate to the Vietnam War and the nuclear arms race. Other subjects include the Cold War and anti-communism. Writings produced for specific projects, committees, or organizations (such as a history of the Mass Defense Office) are filed in SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS AND CONFERENCES. Unidentified drafts and notes are filed by subject in SERIES VIII. RESEARCH.
  [SEE ALSO SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND SUBJECT FILES - unidentified drafts]
- SERIES VII. SPEECHES, (1950-87); 1 linear ft.
  This series contains speech texts, notes, related correspondence, publicity, and research arranged alphabetically by subject or event name. Subjects include anti-communism, nuclear disarmament, international law, Nuremberg, the Civil Rights movement, and the Vietnam War. Papers and addresses given at conferences, tribunals, and other events that were sponsored by organizations in which Kaufman was active are filed in SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS AND CONFERENCES. See also SERIES III. LEGAL PRACTICE for testimonies given by Kaufman in the Trident and Hickam 3 cases; course lectures in SERIES IV. TEACHING, and SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS for clippings publicizing Kaufman's activities, some of which include speaking. Unidentified notes that may also have been used for speeches are filed by subject in SERIES VIII. RESEARCH.
- SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND SUBJECT FILES, (1945-94); 4 linear feet
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject, including five major subject areas: anti-communism, Germany, Nuclear disarmament, Nuremberg and Nazis, and the Vietnam War. There are smaller amounts of material on international law, the Cold War, racism, the Civil Rights movement, U.S. foreign policy, various individuals, and miscellaneous topics. Types of material include articles, legal documents, unpublished writings by others, correspondence, notes and unidentified drafts, newspaper clippings, and printed materials. Kaufman's original file titles have been retained wherever possible.
  Most of these files appear to have been Kaufman's working files that were referred to, and added to, repeatedly over many years for a variety of projects, including legal cases, course lectures, articles, and speeches. Research files that were identified by Kaufman for specific purposes are filed in the appropriate series, such as Research and preparation files under each case in SERIES III. LEGAL PRACTICE, and Course materials in SERIES IV. TEACHING.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
  [See also F.B.I. file on Mary Kaufman, circa 1941-1978 in boxes 1a-1b]
  - Resumes, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles and interviews, 1969-77 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    [SEE ALSO OVERSIZED MATERIALS - Flat file]
  - Education: diploma, honor roll lists, and letter of reference, 1933-34, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Awards and tributes (includes Joseph Forer and other National Lawyers' Guild members), 1945-69, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Travel: passport application, correspondence, and printed materials, 1965-66, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memorabilia, 1924, 1950-56, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous: addresses and notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE (1940-82), .25 linear ft.
  - Family, 1940-65, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Friends and associates
    - Congratulatory letters on establishment of private practice, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - General, 1950-83, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Individuals
      - Baxandall, Rosalyn (includes article on Elizabeth Gurley Flynn), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Caute, David, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - DuBois, W.E.B. and A.C.L.U. (telegram), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Ann Fagan Ginger (includes writings, printed material, and obituary of Harry Sacher), 1969-76, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Hutchins, Grace, 1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Levy, Newman, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Narvaez Ochoa, Evelyn, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Winter, Carl, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Financial and legal (personal): correspondence, documents, bills, 1950-53, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - F.B.I. file on Mary Kaufman, circa 1941-1978 (Box 1a-1b)
    {added in 2006}
- SERIES III. LEGAL PRACTICE
  - General: employment applications, correspondence (includes Joseph Forer and John Abt), bar certificates, and printed materials, 1937-59 (Box 1, Folder 22-25)
  - Early career
    - Works Progress Administration: correspondence, 1934-37 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Frank Scheiner: correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - National Labor Relations Board: correspondence and report, 1939-41, undated (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
    - National War Labor Board
      - General: job evaluations, and committee lists, 1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and legal opinions, 1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
      - Briefs and printed materials, 1945-46, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - National Wage Stabilization Board: evaluations, correspondence, and official documents re: position, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Nuremberg War Crimes Tribunal against I.G. Farben (United States v. Krauch)
    - General: correspondence (includes Telford Taylor and Harry Truman), employment documents, and notes, 1947-49, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Court documents, 1945-48 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
    - Briefs, 1947-48 (Box 2, Folder 6-11)
    - Briefs, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - Final judgement, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Concurring opinion (Justice Paul Herbert), 1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Roechling case judgement, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Smith Act cases
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - Attorneys, defendants, and others involved in Smith Act cases around the country (includes Sydney Berger, Harriet Bouslog, Harold Buchman, Martin Chaucey, George Crockett, Frank Donner, Joseph Forer, Thelma Furry, Simon Gerson, Ann Fagan Ginger, Ernest Goodman, Robert Lewis, John McTernan, David Scribner, Frank Serri, and A.L. Wirin), 1950-55, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - Mailing list, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Families of the Smith Act victims: government memorandum, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Publicity
        - Newsletters (includes Civil Rights Congress, Joint Self Defense Committee), 1951-56 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Research and preparation (alphabetical by subject)
        - A-E (Box 4, Folder 5-8)
        - Informers
          - General (includes article by Frank Donner), 1954-55 (Box 4, Folder 9)
          - Argument on unreliability (includes National Lawyers' Guild), 1949-55, undated (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
          - Force and violence statements, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
          - Individuals, circa 1952-1955, undated
            - Baldwin, Bereniece (Box 4, Folder 13)
            - Budenz, Louis (Box 4, Folder 14)
            - Clontz Ralph and Marlane Kowall (Box 4, Folder 15)
            - Crouch, Paul (Box 4, Folder 16)
            - Hartle, Barbara (Box 4, Folder 17)
            - Lautner, John (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
            - Younglove, Thomas (Box 5, Folder 3)
            - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 4)
          - Subversive Activities Control Board v. American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born (informers in case), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - J-O (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
        - P-Y (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - United States v. Eugene Dennis, et al. [originally U.S. v. William Foster, et al.]
      - Court documents, 1948-59 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
      - Publicity, 1949-51 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Appeals
        [SEE ALSO Smith Act-related cases]
        - U.S. Court of Appeals: briefs and petitions, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 9-11)
        - Supreme Court: briefs, petitions, memoranda, and oral arguments, 1948-51 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
        - Henry Winston and Gil Green: briefs and petitions, 1950-57 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - Gus Hall: briefs, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - John Williamson: correspondence, publicity, and notes, 1953-54 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - Irving Potash: correspondence, billing, documents, and notes, 1956-57, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - William Z. Foster
          - Briefs and petitions, 1959-60 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
          - Correspondence (includes Rowland Watts, Arnold Johnson), 1950-61 (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
          - Court documents, 1959-60 (Box 8, Folder 1)
          - Publicity: clippings and press release, 1959-60 (Box 8, Folder 2)
          - Research and preparation: documents, correspondence, articles, drafts, and notes, 1948-60, undated (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - United States v. Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, et al.
      - Correspondence
        - General (includes Simon Gerson, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, John McTernan), 1951-53 (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Attorneys and others involved (includes Harold Ickes, Robert Minor, Simon Gerson), 1951-53 (Box 9, Folder 2-5)
        - Defendants
          - Alexander Bittleman, 1953-56 (Box 9, Folder 6)
          - Elizabeth Gurley Flynn (includes Roger Baldwin), 1953-76, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
          - Betty Gannett, 1955-56, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
          - Victor Jerome, 1952-55 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
          - Arnold Johnson, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 11)
          - Claudia Jones, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 12)
          - Al Lannon, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 13)
          - Pettis Perry, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 14)
          - Alexander Trachtenberg, 1955, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
          - Weinstock, Louis, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 16)
          - Weinstone, William, 1955-56 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Court documents, 1951-56, undated (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
      - Court documents, 1951-52, undated (Box 10-11)
      - Court documents, 1952-55 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
      - Exhibits: lists, document, 1952, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Publicity (includes Naomi Barko), 1952-54 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
      - Research and preparation (alphabetical by subject)
        - A-C (Box 13, Folder 1-8)
        - Defendants
          - General: notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
          - George Charney: correspondence and notes, 1953-55 (Box 14, Folder 2)
          - Elizabeth Gurley Flynn: statements before court, 1951-52 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
          - Victor Jerome: writings, correspondence, documents, notes, and memorabilia, 1955-1957, undated (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
          - Claudia Jones: correspondence, medical records, documents, printed materials, and notes, 1950-55, undated (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
          - Jacob Mindel: correspondence, notes, and documents, 1951-55, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - D-Jud (Box 14, Folder 10-13)
        - Jury challenge (Box 15, Folder 1-11)
        - K-T (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
        - Witnesses (includes Harvey Matusow and John Lautner), 1952-55, undated (Box 16, Folder 4-11)
          [SEE ALSO Smith Act Cases - General - Informers]
        - Witnesses, 1952, undated (Box 17, Folder 1-6)
      - Transcripts (includes statements by Miles Lane, and Elizabeth Gurley Flynn ), 1952, undated (Box 17, Folder 8-10)
      - Transcripts (includes statement by Frank Serri), 1952-53, undated (Box 18, Folder 1-5)
      - Appeals: briefs, petitions, correspondence (includes Delbert Metzger and A.L. Wirin), and documents, 1953-55 (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
    - United States v. James Forest, et al. and United States v. William Sentner, et al. (St. Louis)
      - Correspondence, 1953-58
        - General (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Attorneys (includes Sydney Berger) (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - Defendants (includes Dorothy and James Forest, Robert and Irma Manewitz, and William Sentner) (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Court documents, 1953-54, undated (Box 20, Folder 4-11)
      - Research and preparation: printed materials, drafts, and notes, 1953-54, undated (Box 20, Folder 12-16)
      - Research and preparation, 1954, undated (cont'd) (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
      - Transcripts (includes statement by Marcus Murphy), 1954 (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
      - Appeals: briefs, petitions, documents, and research, 1954-56, undated (Box 21, Folder 6-12)
      - Appeals: transcripts (includes statement by James Forest), 1954-55, undated (Box 22, Folder 1-10)
    - United States v. Arthur Bary, et al., Denver
      - Correspondence, 1954-57, undated
        - General (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - Attorneys (includes William Bryans, III, Joseph Forer, William V. Hodges, John McTernan, Forrest C. O'Dell, and Samuel Rosenwien) (Box 23, Folder 2-8)
        - Defendants (Arthur and Anna Bary, Marta Correa, Lewis Johnson, Joseph Scherrer, and Harold Zeppelin) (Box 23, Folder 9-13)
      - Court documents, 1954-55, undated (Box 23, Folder 14-18)
      - Publicity, 1955-57 (Box 23, Folder 19-20)
      - Research and preparation, 1955, undated (Box 23, Folder 21-23)
      - Appeal: briefs and documents, 1955-56, undated (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - United States v. George Charney; James Jackson; Alexander Trachtenberg, et al.
      - Correspondence, 1955-56 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Court documents: government's list of documents and exhibits, 1955-56 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Publicity, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Research and preparation, 1956, undated (Box 25, Folder 4-12)
      - Transcript (includes Simon Gerson and Doxey Wilkerson), 30 Apr-17 Sep 1956 (Box 26-29)
      - Appeal
        - Correspondence (includes Ernest Angell, Grace Hutchins, Richard Criley, Doris Fine, Bella Altschuler, Boris Bittker, and George Charney), 1955-58 (Box 30, Folder 1-4)
        - Court documents, 1956-57 (Box 30, Folder 5)
        - Research and preparation, 1953-57, undated (Box 30, Folder 6-10)
  - Smith Act-related cases
    - Attorneys' contempt case (United States v. Harry Sacher, Abraham Isserman, et al.)
      - Briefs and petitions
        - General, 1949-56 (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
        - Disbarment appeals, 1952--61, undated (Box 31, Folder 4-5)
      - Correspondence (includes Leonard Boudin, Abraham Isserman, George Crockett, John McTernan, and Maurice Sugar), 1959-60 (Box 31, Folder 6-8)
      - Court documents, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 1-4)
      - Publicity: clippings and articles (includes I.F. Stone and Harry Sacher Defense Committee), 1950 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
      - Research and preparation, 1950-63, undated (Box 32, Folder 7-13)
    - Trustees of the Bail Fund of the Civil Rights Congress
      - General
        - History and background: memorandum and printed materials, 1949-52 (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Trustees' meetings: minutes and notes, 1947-52, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Briefs, 1951-52, undated (Box 33, Folder 3-5)
      - Correspondence (includes Robert Dunn, Grace Hutchins, Victor Rabinowitz, and Joan Mellen, ), 1951-56, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
      - Court documents, 1949-52 (Box 33, Folder 8-10)
      - Financial records, 1947-53 (Box 33, Folder 11-13)
      - Publicity (includes Howard Fast, I.F. Stone), 1951 (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Research and preparation, 1950-55, undated
        - General (Box 34, Folder 1-5)
        - Bank investigation (Box 34, Folder 6)
        - Subversive Activities Control Board (Box 34, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 34, Folder 8-10)
      - Transcripts
        - Testimonies of Bail Fund trustees in United States v. Eugene Dennis, et al., 1951 (Box 35, Folder 1)
        - United States v. Frederick Vanderbilt Field, et al., circa 1951 (Box 35, Folder 2)
        - Bank investigation, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Other matters
        - United States v. [?] Christoffel (O. John Rogge matter): correspondence, documents, and research, 1951-52, undated (Box 35, Folder 4-8)
        - William Patterson v. United States (CRC tax liability case): correspondence and court documents, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 9)
        - Eisler (?) bail bond matter: correspondence (George Bragdon), 1949-50 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Robert Thompson
      - Contempt case (United States v. Robert Thompson)
        - Briefs and petitions, 1954-58, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence (includes Marcus Goldman and Robert Lewis, 1953-62, undated (Box 36, Folder 3-5)
        - Court documents, 1951-60, undated (Box 36, Folder 6-9)
        - Publicity, 1953, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 10)
        - Research and preparation: A-B, 1957-59, undated (Box 36, Folder 11-15)
        - Research and preparation: M-S, 1950-62, undated (Box 37, Folder 1-7)
        - Transcript, 1953 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Veteran's pension case (Robert Thompson v. Whittier, Administrator of Veterans' Affairs)
        - Briefs, 1960-64, undated (Box 38, Folder 1-7)
        - Correspondence (includes VA, Robert Lewis, Joseph Forer, Robert and Leona Thompson), 1954-66 (Box 38, Folder 8-10)
        - Documents, 1956-65 (Box 39, Folder 1-7)
        - Publicity (A.C.L.U.), 1964 (Box 39, Folder 8)
        - Research and preparation: General, 1950-64, undated (Box 39, Folder 9-10)
        - Research and preparation: B-T, 1950-64, undated (Box 40, Folder 1-9)
        - Transcript (Board of Veterans Appeals hearing), 1963 (Box 40, Folder 10)
      - Estate settlement
        - Correspondence (includes Sylvia Thompson), 1965-68 (Box 41, Folder 1)
        - Court documents, 1965-69 (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Disbursement of estate and expenses: correspondence, receipts, and notes, 1959-68, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
        - James Thompson (son): correspondence, notes, and financial records, 1965-68 (Box 41, Folder 4)
        - Research and preparation, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Arlington cemetery case (Sylvia Thompson v. McNamara, et al.)
        - Brief (A.C.L.U.), 1967 (Box 41, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence (includes Joel Hoffman and Lawrence Speiser), 1965-66 (Box 41, Folder 7)
        - Court documents, 1966-68 (Box 41, Folder 8)
        - Publicity (includes copies of additional correspondence, documents, and publicity), 1966, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
        - Research and preparation, circa 1958-74 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC) cases
    - General Electric employees, Bridgeport, CT: correspondence, notes, billing, printed materials, and clippings, 1956-58 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - David Fine: correspondence, billing, and notes, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Oakley Johnson: documents, notes, printed materials, and publicity, 1952-57 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Newark, N.J. (includes Manuel Cantor, John Norman, Louis Malinow, and John Karakos): correspondence, notes, and publicity, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous: documents, and procedures, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board (S.A.C.B.) cases
    [SEE ALSO SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS AND CONFERENCES - National Lawyers' Guild - Projects - C.P.-U.S.A. v. S.A.C.B]
    - S.A.C.B. v. Council on African Affairs
      - Correspondence (W. Alpheus Hunton), 1955 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Court documents, 1952-55, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Publicity: newsletters and clipping, 1948-55, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Research and preparation, 1944-55, undated (Box 42, Folder 9-11)
    - Louisiana [S.A.C.B.] v. Junesh Jenkins
      - Correspondence, memoranda, and billing (includes Leonard Boudin, Oakley Johnson, Corliss Lamont), 1957-58 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Court documents, 1957, undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - Publicity (includes W.E.B. DuBois), 1957-58 (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - Research and preparation (includes Oakley Johnson), 1957-58 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - S.A.C.B. v. W.E.B. DuBois Clubs of America: documents and printed materials, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Passport and immigration cases
    - General: correspondence, documents, printed materials, and notes, 1947-64 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Immigration cases: correspondence (includes International Workers Order and American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born), documents, and notes, 1950-53, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
      [SEE ALSO Bail Fund of the Civil Rights Congress]
    - Passports: correspondence (includes Robert Jackson, Corliss Lamont and James Jackson), documents, printed materials, and notes, 1957-60s (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Dmytryshyn, Andrew: documents and notes, 1950, undated (Box 43, Folder 4-5)
    - International Workers' Order: documents, drafts, and notes, 1948-49, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Willie McGee v. [State of Mississippi]
    - Brief and petition (by Bella Abzug), 1950 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (includes Harriet Bouslog, Myer Symonds), 1950-51 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Court documents, 1951 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Publicity: clippings, 1945-51, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Research and preparation (includes article by Oakley Johnson), 1947-51, undated (Box 44, Folder 5-8)
  - National Guardian and the American Newspaper Guild: correspondence, memoranda, drafts, notes, and printed materials, 1948-1950, undated (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
  - Cuban banks: briefs and research, 1959-63 (Box 45, Folder 3-5)
  - Gary Powers trial (Moscow): notes, drafts, and publicity, 1960 (Box 45, Folder 6-7)
  - New York v. Molina Del Rio: documents, publicity, and briefs, 1960-64, undated (Box 46, Folder 1-5)
  - Grossman v. Joan Baez: memorandum, 1963 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    [CLOSED until Baez's death]
  - International Publishers
    - General: memoranda, correspondence (includes James Allen), documents, printed materials, and notes, 1963-1965, undated (Box 46, Folder 7-8)
    - International Publishers v. Hotel Belmont (re: Elizabeth Gurley Flynn speaking): correspondence, court documents, and printed materials, 1963, undated (Box 46, Folder 9-11)
    - International Publishers v. Hilton Hotel (re: anniversary and Alexander Trachtenberg's birthday celebration): correspondence, court documents, press release, drafts, notes, and printed materials, 1963-65, undated (Box 46, Folder 12-15)
  - Dialogue Publications: correspondence, documents, printed materials, and notes, 1961-1966, undated (Box 46, Folder 16-19)
  - Harlem 6 (New York v. Wallace Baker, et al.)
    - Correspondence (includes William Kunstler, Conrad Lynn, Gene Ann Condon, Victor Herwitz, and William Stringfellow), 1964-1967 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Court documents, 1964-1967 (Box 47, Folder 2-3)
    - Publicity, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Research and preparation, 1961-67 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Amicus curiae (Charter Group for a Pledge of Conscience): brief, correspondence, minutes, drafts, petition (by James Baldwin), and printed materials, 1966-67 (Box 47, Folder 6-7)
  - Julius Zupan and United Union Painters: correspondence, printed materials, and notes, 1964-66, undated (Box 47, Folder 8-9)